Guide to the Bruce Boling Irish Language Papers AIA.062
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III. Secondary Source Materials, 1905-2001
  - Haleiken. "Notes on World View and Semantic Categories: Some Warlpiri Examples." Features and Projectoins, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Harris, John. "English in the North of Ireland." Languages in the British Aisles, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Harris, Ruth-Ann M. "American Imagined, American Realized: New Perspectives on the American Letter," American Conference for Irish Studies, St. Louis, Missouri, Apr 1990 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Hickey, Raymond. "Salient Features of Irish Syntax." Lingua Posnaniensis, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Hingeston, F. C. (ed). Royal and Historical Letters During the Reign of Henry the Fourth (1860), circa 1970-2000 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - "Historic Dublin Maps." The National Library of Ireland Historical Documents, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Hoijer, Harry. "The Apachean Verb" Parts 1-5. International Journal of American Linguistics, 1945-1949 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Hoijer, Harry. "Classificatory Verb Stems in the Apachean Languages." International Journal of American Linguistics, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Hollingsworth, Gerelyn. "Irish Quakers in Colonial Pennsylvania: A Forgotten Segment of Society." Journal of the Lancaster County Historical Society, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Hornjatkevyči, A. J. "Ukrainian Conjugation." International Journal of Slavic Linguistics and Poetics, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Immigration and Ethnic Groups in America Bibliography, circa 1973 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Inglis, Henry D. Ireland in 1834: A Journey Throughout Ireland, During the Spring, Summer, and Autumn of 1834, undated (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Jackson, Kenneth. "The Regular and Irregular Verbs as Plougrescant." Indo-Celtics: Gedaechtnischrift fuer Alf Sommerfelt, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Jakobson, Roman. "Shifters, Verbal Categories, and the Russian Verb." Russian Language Project: Department of Slavic Languages and Literatures, Harvard University, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Jakobson, Roman. "The Slavic God Veles and His Indo-European Cognates." Studi Linguistici in Onore di Vittoro Pisani, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Janda, Laura A. "The Mapping of Elements of Cognitive Space onto Grammatical Relations: An Example from Russian Verbal Prefixation." Topics in Cognitive Linguistics, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Jasanoff, Jay. "The r-endings of the IE Middle." Diesprache, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Klaiman, M. H. "Affectedness and Control: A Typology of Voice Systems." Passive Voice, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Langacker, Ronald W. "The Nature of Grammatical Violence." Topics in Cognitive Linguistics, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Langacker, Ronald W. "A Usage-Based Model." Topics in Cognitive Linguistics, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Langacker, Ronald W. "A View of Linguistic Semantics." Topics in Cognitive Linguistics, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Letter Book of Sir Author Chichester, 1612-1614 (Dudley Edwards), circa 1970-2000 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Levin, Jules F. "Iconicity in Lithuanian." Folia Slavica, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Library Local Studies Panel (Omagh) "Irish Periodicals First Published Before 1901: A Union List of Northern Ireland Library Holdings", 1995 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Lincoln, Bruce. "The Indo-European Myth of Creation." History of Religions, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Lincoln, Bruce. "The Lord of the Dead." History of Religions, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Lincoln, Bruce. "Treatment of Hair and Fingernails Among the Indo-Europeans." History of Religions, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Lunt, Horace G. "On the Study of Slavic Accentuation." Word, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Lyttle, W. G. Betsy Gray or, Hearts of Down, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - MacGowan, Michael. The Hard Road to Klondike, circa 1970-2000 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Mason, William Shaw. A Statistical Account of Parochial Survey of Ireland, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Mayo, Peter J. A Grammar of Byelorussian, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - McCafferty, Kevin. "Rungates Revisited." Causeway, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Mcgee, Thomas d'Arcy. "The Irish in British America." The Irish Position in British and in Republican North American (1866), circa 1970-2000 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Meir, Colin. "Status and Style in Carleton's Traits and Stones of the Irish Peasantry." Rural Ireland, Real Ireland, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Mescon, Enid. "From County Cork to New York with the Jacksons.", 1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Meyer, Kuno. Über die älteste irische Dichtung: I. Rhythmische alliteriende Reimlosestrophen, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Meyer, Kuno. Über die älteste irische Dichtung: II. Rhythmische alliterierende Reimlosestrophen, 1914 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Miller, Kerby A. "Emigration as Exile: Cultural Hegemony in Post-Famine Ireland", Mar 1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Milroy, James. Regional Accents of English: Belfast, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Montogmery, Michael. "The Celtic Element in American English", 2000 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Montgomery, Michael. "An Early Letter in Ulster Scots."Ullans, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Montgomery, Michael. "How Scotch-Irish is Your English?", undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Montgomery, Michael. "The Irish Contributions to American English Vocabulary.", undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Montgomery, Michael. "Trans-Atlantic Connections Betwen Varieties of English: the Case of the Plural Verbals.", 1989 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Murphy, Michael J. Tyrone Folk Quest, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Neubert, Albrecht. "Die Sprache als unmittelbare Wirklichkeit des Gedankens?", 1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Nolan, Brian. "Passive Voice Constructions in Modern Irish." Proceedings of the High Desea Linguistic Society, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Ó Cadhain, Máirtín. Consain na Gaeilge (The Consonants of Irish), 1960 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - O'Dúill, Gréagóir. "Emigrant Letters from the Donegal Gaeltacht." The Irish Language in the United States, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - O'Foghludha, Risteárd. Donnchadh Ruadh Mac Conmara, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Oceans of Consolation: Letters and Irish Immigration to Australia, circa 1994 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Old Church Slavonic: Glossary and Reading Selections, circa 1970-2000 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Ordnance Survey: Memoirs of Ireland, 1830-1840, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Papnotte, Wolf. "A Discourse Perspective on Tense and Aspect in Standard Modern Greek and English." Topics in Cognitive Linguistics, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Payne, Robert A. Briefe Description of Ireland (1958), circa 1970-2000 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Phillips, Louis. "You Too Can Learn to Flay Your Foes." Smithsonian, Mar 1991 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Pleimionn, Seaghan. Dante Agus Beata Donncada Ruaid Mic Conmara, circa 1929 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Potter, George W. To the Golden Door: The Story of the Irish in Ireland and America (1960), circa 1970-2000 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Puhuel, Joan. "Remus et Frater." History of Religions (1960), 1975 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - "Pathdowney-Born Priest Brought Christianity to Californian Mine Fields." The Leinster Express, Jan 7, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Robinson, Phillip. "Jonathan Swift; His Early Writings in Ulster-Scots?" Ullans, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - The Royal Irish Academy. "Dictionary of the Irish Language and Contributions to a Dictionary of the Irish Language.", circa 1966 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Sasse, Hans J. "Typology of Aspect Systems.", circa 1970-2000 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Schmalstieg, William R. "Some Uses of the Genitive Case in Old Bulgarian.", 1985 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Silverstein, Michael. "Language Structure and Linguistic Ideology." Conference on Non-Slavic Languages of the USSR, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Society and Culture in the Congested Districts (1894), circa 1970-2000 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Special Report on Surnames in Ireland (1909), circa 1970-2000 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Staal, Frits. "Ritual Syntax." Sanskrit and Indian Studies: Essays in Honor of Daniel H. H. Ingalls, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Sulima, R. "Wygnancy: Pionierzy", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Synge, John M. The Aran Islands and Other Writings, after 1962 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Taimy, Leonard. "The Relation of Grammar to Cognition." Topics in Cognitive Linguistics, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Tesnière, Lucien. "L'Emploi des temps en français." Bulletin de la Faculté des Lettres de Strasbourg, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Thurneysen, Rudolf. Die Bürgschaft im Irischen Recht, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Thurneysen, Rudolf. Irisches Recht I. Dire. Ein Altirischer Rechstext, II. Ze den Standen in Irland, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Thurneysen, Rudolf. Morands Fürstenspiegel, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Thurneysen, Rudolf. Zu Irischen Handschriften und Litteraturdenkmälern, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Traynor, Michael. The English Dialect of Donegal. Dublin: The Royal Academy (I), 1953 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Traynor, Michael. The English Dialect of Donegal. Dublin: The Royal Academy (II), 1953 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Trudgill, Peter and Jean Hanah. "Scottish and Irish English." International English: A Guide to Varieties of Standard English, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Tuggy, David. "Nánvatl Causative/Applicatives in Cognitive Grammar." Topics in Cognitive Grammar, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Ulster Historical Foundation. Directory of Irish Family Research, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Ulster Plantation Papers, 1608-1613 (T. W. Moody), 1938 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - van Schooneveld, Cornelius H. "Paradigmatic Structure and Syntactic Relations." The Prague School and Its Legacy, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Wakefield, Edward. An Account of Ireland, Statistical and Political (1812), undated (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Watkins, Calvert. "NAM, RA GUD UDU in Hittite: Indo-European Poetic Language and the Folk Taxonomy of Wealth.", 1979 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Waugh, Linda R. "The Poetic Function in the Theory of Roman Jakobson." Poetics Today, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Weiss, Daniel. "Kongruenz vs. Kongruenzlosigkeit." Zeitschrift für slavische Philologie, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Wierzbicka, Anna. The Case for Surface Case, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Wierzbicka, Anna. "Case Marking and Human Nature." Australian Journal of Linguistics, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Wierzbicka, Anna. "Different Cultures, Different Languages, Different Speech Acts." Journal of Pragmatics, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Wilson, James. The Dialect of Robert Burns as Spoken in Central Ayrshire (1923), circa 1970-2000 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Wilson, James. Lowland Scotch as Spoken in the Lower Strathearn District of Perthshire (1915), circa 1970-2000 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Woodman, Nancy. "Ła' T'áá Bita'ígóó Njigháá Nt'éego Hahane'" / "The Story of an Orphan", after 1954 (Box 9, Folder 64)